<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Linguistrix</title>
    <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Linguistrix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.linguistrix.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Not bashful to admit that I didn&#39;t know what it meant</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2017/11/not-bashful-to-admit-that-i-didnt-know-what-it-meant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2017/11/not-bashful-to-admit-that-i-didnt-know-what-it-meant/</guid>
      <description>Quick question. Answer instictively without trying to over-analyze.
 The word bashful is closest in meaning to: A) Shy B) Arrogant
 About 6 years ago, I wrote about how I had discovered that I had been pronouncing awry, well, differently. I had another such moment of surprise last night, when I realized that the word bashful doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean what I used to this it does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another woe of non-phonetic writing systems</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2017/01/yet-another-woe-of-non-phonetic-writing-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 15:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2017/01/yet-another-woe-of-non-phonetic-writing-systems/</guid>
      <description>I was in Mexico last week and was quite excited to try my Spanish there. I studied some Spanish 3–4 years ago using Michel Thomas courses, and did a few levels on Duolingo, and combined with my French, I can get a general sense of simple written Spanish, but I had literally zero on-ground speaking experience. There are plenty of Spanish speakers in California, so it&amp;rsquo;s not difficult at all to find people to chat with if you really care, but it somehow never happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review: Arrival</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/12/movie-review-arrival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 09:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/12/movie-review-arrival/</guid>
      <description>Arpan suggested that I review Arrival, a SciFi movie that has as its lead character—wait for it—a linguistics professor. I first thought of writing a review without spoilers but realized that it&amp;rsquo;d be impossible to write about the linguistically relevant parts of the movie without giving it all away, so I scrapped that plan. This review specifically addresses only and all linguistic aspects of the movie, so it might feel like nitpicking if you are not interested in all that stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Through the Language Glass by Guy Deutscher</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/10/book-review-through-the-language-glass-by-guy-deutscher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 21:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/10/book-review-through-the-language-glass-by-guy-deutscher/</guid>
      <description>RVC recently told me about Through the Language Glass, a book by Guy Deutscher (GD), an Israeli linguist, that is based around the premise of &amp;lsquo;linguistic relativity&amp;rsquo;. Ordinarily, hearing those two words together evokes a bit of a fight / flight response in me, so I read the excerpts he sent with some trepidation. I realized that, far from being yet another piece fawning over linguistic relativity, this book actually seemed to be addressing many questions I had about this topic but had never seen properly answered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should be India’s common script?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/07/what-should-be-indias-common-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 17:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/07/what-should-be-indias-common-script/</guid>
      <description>I have a lot of interest in writing systems, which is why you will find a lot of posts on this blog around them. A few years ago, I wrote about the Bharati script, which was touted as an attempt to create a universal script for Indian languages. I had expressed measured skepticism about the idea, but had also said I would like to see the script, and luckily, was contacted by Chetan Shenoy, an undergrad from IIT Madras, who works under Prof Chakravarthy, the creator of the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindi Cryptic Crosswords</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2015/09/hindi-cryptic-crosswords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 17:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2015/09/hindi-cryptic-crosswords/</guid>
      <description>I recently set the &amp;lsquo;question paper&amp;rsquo; for the Hindi Word Games General Championship (GC) 1 at IIT Bombay. Here are the links to the question set and the solutions. As part of the competition, I decided to put in a round of Hindi Cryptic Puzzles. Cryptic Crosswords are very popular in English, but haven&amp;rsquo;t got much of a traction in the Hindi world. Regular crossword puzzles are fairly common—I remember solving the crossword in the Dainik Bhaskar growing up, but cryptics are relatively unchartered territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pranav Mistry and our problem with accents</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2014/01/pranav-mistry-and-our-problem-with-accents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 18:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2014/01/pranav-mistry-and-our-problem-with-accents/</guid>
      <description>Pranav Mistry was one of the speakers at IIT Bombay&amp;rsquo;s Techfest this year. He rose to fame in 2010 for his TED Talk on Sixth Sense, a wearable gestural interface that augments the physical world around us with digital information and lets us use natural hand gestures to interact with it (Description sourced from his website).
  Since then, he has been in and out of limelight, and has generally been on the receiving end of a lot of (well deserved) love and admiration from Indians, especially because he comes off as a &amp;lsquo;son of the soil&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One script to bind them all</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/07/one-script-to-bind-them-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/07/one-script-to-bind-them-all/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, I came across a few news reports that a professor from IIT Madras (Professor V Srinivas Chakravarthy) has developed a script (called Bharati) to &amp;ldquo;unify 22 Indian languages&amp;rdquo;. As a script-enthusiast, I was of course slightly interested.
There is a lot of self-congratulatory rhetoric in India about how Indian scripts are very &amp;lsquo;scientific&amp;rsquo;. On the contrary, the English script (which, in most cases, is the only other kind of script most Indians know) is criticized for being arbitrary, ambiguous, unscientific, what have you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could better science reporting standards at the BBC improve the quality of their articles?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/02/could-better-science-reporting-standards-at-the-bbc-improve-the-quality-of-their-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 19:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/02/could-better-science-reporting-standards-at-the-bbc-improve-the-quality-of-their-articles/</guid>
      <description>I just came across this article on the BBC Website (Could a new phonetic alphabet promote world peace?) because it was posted in the /r/badlinguistics sub-reddit, and for good reason.
It is such a remarkable mix of bad linguistics and general cluelessness that I would have thought that even with media&amp;rsquo;s generally low standards of science (especially language) reporting, something like this would not have made the cut.
First of all, I am not sure why they even chose to write a whole article around this SaypU thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orders When Pizza Yoda</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/01/orders-when-pizza-yoda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 05:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/01/orders-when-pizza-yoda/</guid>
      <description>A comic that was doing the rounds a few months ago keeps getting revived every once in a while when it gets discovered by a new bunch of people. The comic shows Yoda ordering pizza over the phone, but unable to get his order across because of his mangled word order. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to not feel pity for the battered Yoda shown in the last frame as he sits biting on a sandwich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have App!</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/01/we-have-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 08:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/01/we-have-app/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I saw an Onion Tech Trends video: HP Offers &amp;lsquo;That Cloud Thing Everyone Is Talking About.
  The whole video is funny, but what really cracked me up was when the HP spokesman says, at 1:32, We have App.
Evidently, many other people found it funny too—the top comment on the YouTube video makes a reference to that statement, and a quick search I did on Google showed me that this particular line was tweeted and written about quite a bit when the video was launched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WiFi Free</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/01/wifi-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 07:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/01/wifi-free/</guid>
      <description>When I visited the recently opened Starbucks near Horniman Circle, I noticed this on the glass door:
  The fact that the word free has two senses in English is often brought up because the difference in the two senses is sometimes critical/relevant. Especially in the FOSS (Free and Open Software) world, the distinction is often explained as Free as in free speech, not as in free beer, to disambiguate the two senses: one of freedom and another of not having to pay anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hinglish Project</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/12/the-hinglish-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 20:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/12/the-hinglish-project/</guid>
      <description>I had heard about the Hinglish project back in June when Sindhu shared the link to their website on her status. I had since forgotten about it, only to be reminded of it some time ago when an Incredible India! video featuring the project was shared by many people on Facebook. The video has over 70000 views now. A few people even pinged me with the link and suggested that I do a Linguistrix post on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maine Basanti Ko Nahaate Huey Dekha</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/11/maine-basanti-ko-nahaate-huey-dekha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 12:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/11/maine-basanti-ko-nahaate-huey-dekha/</guid>
      <description>This cartoon appeared today in my Facebook feed:
  I&amp;rsquo;m posting it on Linguistrix because it&amp;rsquo;s a rather cute display of syntactic ambiguity, and for a change, it&amp;rsquo;s in Hindi. Syntactic ambiguity is when a particular sentence can be parsed in more than one grammatically correct ways, each with a different meaning. A popular example is I shot an elephant in my pajamas, which has not two but three parsings—either I was wearing my pyjamas, or the elephant was inside my pajamas, or that the elephant was wearing my pajamas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciTech Majlis and Arabic Roots</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/scitech-majlis-and-arabic-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 14:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/scitech-majlis-and-arabic-roots/</guid>
      <description>The Society for Promotion for Undergraduate Research (SPUR) recently launched &amp;lsquo;Scitech Majlis&amp;rsquo;: Weekly group discussion session about science and technology. The name gave rise to a bit of buzz because of the use of the Urdu word majlis (مجلس, मजलिस). When I first heard it, it sounded a bit tone-deaf to me—the two words didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to lend well to compounding, but whatever.
Anyhow, I am no Urdu expert but I do know of some good places where we can look, and I went to my trusted resource, Platts&amp;rsquo; Dictionary of Urdu, Classical Hindi and English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Sex—Female Organs and Aromatic Beans</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/vanilla-sexfemale-organs-and-aromatic-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 15:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/vanilla-sexfemale-organs-and-aromatic-beans/</guid>
      <description>The SMBC comic from a few days ago goes like this:
  Something didn&amp;rsquo;t seem right about the whole thing but SMBC is usually grounded on at least some fact, so I decided to explore, and it turned out to be more interesting than I had earlier thought.
It turns out that the term vanilla (used to describe the beans) does come from the Latin root vagina, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as simple as that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Do You Mind Trap</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/the-do-you-mind-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 05:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/the-do-you-mind-trap/</guid>
      <description>I was browsing a website on my phone using the Dolphin browser when a prompt came up. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take a screenshot, so I am paraphrasing what the prompt said:
 In order to improve this application, would you mind giving your experience a star rating?
 Below the question were two command buttons
 No | Rate
 &amp;lsquo;Uh-0h,&amp;rsquo; I said to no one in particular.
When someone asks me something by phrasing it in the Do You Mind form, it&amp;rsquo;s often an invitation for trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank God It’s Jummabar</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/thank-god-its-jummabar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 03:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/thank-god-its-jummabar/</guid>
      <description>You know that politics (and its reporting in the media) in your country is hitting a new low when they take Mamata Bannerjee and then criticize her for a silly linguistic foible.
She threatened to pull her men out of the union on Jummabar, leading to hue and cry not over the pulling out but on her choice of word—Jummabar.
TOI has been kind enough to give us a quick Urdu lesson about the Urdu word for Friday:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cabinet Ministers’ Linguistic Skills</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/cabinet-ministers-linguistic-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 05:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/cabinet-ministers-linguistic-skills/</guid>
      <description>This post is about a piece of news that&amp;rsquo;s more than a year old, but I am posting it now because 1. Linguistrix didn&amp;rsquo;t exist back then, and 2. the post is relevant in light of my recent post on India&amp;rsquo;s linguistic plurality.
This comes from the days when the Jan Lokpal Movement was in full swing and there were talks and discussions between Team Anna and the government on an almost daily basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coalgate and Snowclones</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/coalgate-and-snowclones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 19:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/coalgate-and-snowclones/</guid>
      <description>As the government faces the aftermath of another scam, the name with which media is referring to that scam is of some linguistic interest.
The Indian Coal Allocation Scam is being widely referred to as Coalgate, a variation on the Watergate scandal with the added punny bonus of it sounding the same as a popular toothpaste brand.
The Watergate scandal, apart from leading to then president Richard Nixon&amp;rsquo;s resignation, became immortal when countless scandals around the world began getting named after it, all ending in -gate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Verb: Toolder</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/new-verb-toolder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 04:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/new-verb-toolder/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a while in human history comes a time when a semantic gap needs to be filled; when a word needs to be born to take on the responsibility it was destined to. A day shall come when lexicographers would lay their pens to rest and take a well deserved retirement. That day is not today. Today, we create a new word.
Toolder [verb, transitive]
Pronuncation: ˈtul.dɚ (tool-duhr), ˈtul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The double-edged sword of India’s linguistic plurality</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/the-double-edged-sword-of-indias-linguistic-plurality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 15:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/the-double-edged-sword-of-indias-linguistic-plurality/</guid>
      <description>A lot has been said and written about India’s linguistic diversity and about our love for the English language. I have seen Indians being described as slaves of the British or slaves of the English language. I have heard them being accused of harbouring an absurd fascination (/fetish) for English. Not content with attacking Indians for their weird fascination for foreign imports, people then continue on to dissing English, calling it backward, stupid, regressive, and a dozen other adjectives that aren’t even defined over the domain of languages as far as linguistics is concerned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squeezing babies and cutting steel</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/squeezing-babies-and-cutting-steel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 15:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/squeezing-babies-and-cutting-steel/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, I saw the Olive Oil/Baby Oil meme resurfacing on Facebook. For those not familiar with it, it shows the image of a rather shocked looking baby with the caption If olive oil is made of olives, then&amp;#8230; what is baby oil made of?
  My heart goes out to the baby, because compound nouns in English can be very very tricky. There is no standard form for interpreting the meaning of a compound noun X-Y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 YEAR!</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 05:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/09/1-year/</guid>
      <description>Today, Linguistrix turns one year old. It&amp;rsquo;s been a great journey, and I have always enjoyed posting on this blog. I know that posting frequency has reduced in the past few months, but I will try to raise it and bring the blog back to how it was earlier.
I have a few things planned for celebrating Linguistrix&amp;rsquo;s birthday. First off, I am doing an AMA about linguistics and languages on Reddit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prescriptivists try Zoology</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/07/prescriptivists-try-zoology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 14:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/07/prescriptivists-try-zoology/</guid>
      <description>When I was a kid, there was this joke that I often read in one of those magazines for children (I think it was Champak). It was rather lame, but I realized a few days ago that it presented a rather nice analogy of the raging debate between prescriptivism and descriptivism that goes on in academic circles (about language) and so I present an adapted version:
 One day, two friends (a prescriptivist and a descriptivist) are walking inside a forest, when they suddenly realize that a fierce looking lion has been stalking them and looks like it&amp;rsquo;s about to attack them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mess that is the English spelling system</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/06/the-mess-that-is-the-english-spelling-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 04:18:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/06/the-mess-that-is-the-english-spelling-system/</guid>
      <description>The latest XKCD reads:
The first part is a reference to the cheesy pick-up line &amp;lsquo;If I could rearrange the alphabet, I&amp;rsquo;d put U and I together&amp;rsquo;.
The irregularity of the English spelling system is part of folk-lore now. You have countless poems and articles and whatnots, all trying to hammer in the fact that English pronunciation is the work of the Devil.
English wasn&amp;rsquo;t always this way. Let&amp;rsquo;s travel through time to the 14th century and listen to a recitation of the General Prologue to Canterbury Tales by Geoffrey Chaucer in Middle English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, the Hindustan Times printed my letter, but…</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/06/so-the-hindustan-times-printed-my-letter-but/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 17:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/06/so-the-hindustan-times-printed-my-letter-but/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, I wrote an open letter to the Hindustan Times in which I criticized their Sunday columnist Karan Thapar for often putting together his columns based on boring email forwards full of banalities. It was almost as if his grandson (assuming he has one) wrote those columns based on whatever the funniest joke in his kindergarten class was. I say this because I think it was around 1st standard that the &amp;lsquo;P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Incentivize Word Rage</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/06/dont-incentivize-word-rage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 04:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/06/dont-incentivize-word-rage/</guid>
      <description>Word Rage is a common phenomenon that particularly affects the intellectual community, whose members apparently can&amp;rsquo;t convince themselves of their intellectuality unless they swear bodily harm against people who use words they don&amp;rsquo;t like or misplace apostrophes or other sundry stuff. It also serves as a classic ad-hominem tactic—if you can&amp;rsquo;t find any sensible counter-argument to someone&amp;rsquo;s claims, criticize his spelling or usage instead and pat your back for a job well done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting your speech for non-fluent speakers</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/05/adapting-your-speech-for-non-fluent-speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 14:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/05/adapting-your-speech-for-non-fluent-speakers/</guid>
      <description>I recently answered a question on Quora that is also relevant for this blog, so I am posting it here. When speaking to someone who does not seem to be a fluent English speaker, should I &amp;ldquo;dumb down&amp;rdquo; my diction and vocabulary, or is that condescending and presumptuous?{#__w2_mw0UOKH_link}
My answer
It is very easy to make your speech easier to understand to the listener without &amp;lsquo;dumbing&amp;rsquo; it down. Humans anyhow unconsciously accommodate their speech 1 to suit their listener.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open letter to the Hindustan Times</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/05/open-letter-to-the-hindustan-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 02:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/05/open-letter-to-the-hindustan-times/</guid>
      <description>Dear Hindustan Times,
I will jump straight to the point. Why does Karan Thapar get to fill precious center-page real estate of the Sunday newspaper with content found in boring email forwards? I mean, I know it&amp;rsquo;s your editorial decision and all, but I had expected that you&amp;rsquo;d give more value to your Sunday center-page, otherwise filled with useful and interesting content. You know, if you want your readers to read fascinating and funny stuff about the English language taken from the Web, I would suggest reprinting any of Language Log&amp;rsquo;s posts instead of the mindless drivel that you let KT write just because, well, he&amp;rsquo;s KT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mere dil ka chain tere do mast mast nainon ke dwaara le jaaya gaya</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/04/mere-dil-ka-chain-tere-do-mast-mast-nainon-ke-dwaara-le-jaaya-gaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/04/mere-dil-ka-chain-tere-do-mast-mast-nainon-ke-dwaara-le-jaaya-gaya/</guid>
      <description>A pic was shared like crazy on Facebook in the last few weeks—
  This comic is factually incorrect, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good demonstration of how most people are confused about what actual Active and Passive voice is, and mostly just assume it to be random rearrangement of words.
In the comic, the teacher asks the students to give examples of Active Voice and Passive Voice. The smartass kid replies with two lines from the song _Tere mast mast do nain_ from the movie Dabangg, thereby also complimenting his teacher&amp;rsquo;s eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is mediaphobe a word? Notes from the PAF</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/04/is-mediaphobe-a-word-notes-from-the-paf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 18:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/04/is-mediaphobe-a-word-notes-from-the-paf/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s PAF (Performing Arts Festival) raised an interesting linguistic issue—what makes a word a word?
In the PAF, Rajiv Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s character was called a mediaphobe since he was scared of facing the media. He retaliated, in almost a childishly innocent manner, by saying that _mediaphobe_ wasn&amp;rsquo;t even a word and so he couldn&amp;rsquo;t be called one. He went on to say that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t _be_ a mediaphobe for the same reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermione teaches Shakira: It’s Rabiósa, not Rabiosá</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/hermione-teaches-shakira-its-rabi%C3%B3sa-not-rabios%C3%A1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 15:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/hermione-teaches-shakira-its-rabi%C3%B3sa-not-rabios%C3%A1/</guid>
      <description>When you combine an awesome Harry Potter reference with Spanish phonology, you get a winner. This has got to be the funniest thing I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the recent past:
Since this is Linguistrix, let me add a few lines about the points of linguistic interest in this gag. Spanish pronunciation is delightfully easy and predictable with a very regular spelling system. Words usually have only one stressed syllable, and it is the last syllable, except when the word ends in N or S or a vowel, in which case it&#39;s the penultimate syllable (Michel Thomas calls this rule the Nose Rule).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The critical mass of goodness</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/the-critical-mass-of-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 07:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/the-critical-mass-of-goodness/</guid>
      <description>The country was galvanized last year by the whole Jan Lokpal Movement, and a lot was said for and against the movement, its leaders and cheerleaders, and the thousands of Indians who poured into the streets in the largest display of public outrage in recent times. While we are all fashionably outraged at the way politicians misuse public money with impunity, a small look at the way we lead our daily lives is enough to show that what happens in the order of millions of rupees is just a bigger manifestation of a phenomenon that is integral to our everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A ton of tons</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/a-ton-of-tons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 10:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/a-ton-of-tons/</guid>
      <description>This Friday, Sachin Tendulkar completed 100 international cricket centuries and did something that would have been considered impossible by many—prevent millions of Indians from realizing that the new budget is going to make prices rise even more. He also gave everyone an excuse to come up with all kinds of puns involving his name and the word Ton. I wonder if someone&amp;rsquo;s said Ton Ton Gopaal yet.
Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t follow cricket all that much—I mean, I do watch a couple of matches a year to justify my Indian citizenship, and I keep track of big events such as this one, but that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chutiya Community and Etymological Notes</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/the-chutiya-community-and-etymological-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 04:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/the-chutiya-community-and-etymological-notes/</guid>
      <description>As you may have read, Facebook has attracted the anger of—and I swear there is no other way to put it—the Chutiya community from Assam by blocking many Facebook profiles which mentioned Chutiya as their last name. This is of course a bit ironic coming from a company who&amp;rsquo;s CEO&amp;rsquo;s sister is named Randi (Hindi insult meaning prostitute), but let&amp;rsquo;s not digress.
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know Hindi, _Chutiya_ is an expletive that means _fool/idiot_ but is pretty offensive and insulting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you think it’s disgusting, too bad for you.</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/if-you-think-its-disgusting-too-bad-for-you./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 19:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/if-you-think-its-disgusting-too-bad-for-you./</guid>
      <description>[This post is second in the series of general posts on Linguistrix (the first one was Stupid Analogues are like Stupid Analogies). I choose to include such posts on the blog because I find the topic to be of significant intellectual/academic interest.]        [This post is second in the series of general posts on Linguistrix (the first one was Stupid Analogues are like Stupid Analogies).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How bad is sexy?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/how-bad-is-sexy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 11:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/how-bad-is-sexy/</guid>
      <description>Mamta Sharma, the head of the National Commission for Women, India, has gotten herself into trouble by saying (at a function) that girls shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be offended if guys call them sexy, as it&amp;rsquo;s a word with positive connotations of beauty and charm. Her exact quote (or at least what HT reported) was:
 Boys pass comments on girls terming them sexy but sexy means beautiful and charming. We should not see it in negative sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EYE-SEAT or E-SEAT?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/eye-seat-or-e-seat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 15:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/eye-seat-or-e-seat/</guid>
      <description>[Edit: A few days after this post was written, the powers-that-be decided to retain the name JEE for the new entrance test that would replace JEE+AIEEE combo from next year]
The JEE and AIEEE, two flagship examinations that used to be conducted for students aspiring to secure an admission into the IITs/NITs are going to be replaced by an exam called ISEET (Indian Science Engineering Eligibility Test). There are of course loads of issues surrounding this decision that the government took, but none that come under the purview of Linguistrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The opposite of progress—deconstructing the pun</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/the-opposite-of-progressdeconstructing-the-pun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/the-opposite-of-progressdeconstructing-the-pun/</guid>
      <description>A joke (sorta lame but, whatever) that has been going around on the internet since ages (if pro is the opposite of con, what&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of progress?) was finally picked up and printed on the front page of Mumbai Mirror, in light of today&amp;rsquo;s civic body elections, thus ensuring that the handful of people who hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard it earlier are now aware of it. The grammatical mistake (IT shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been there) and the bad spacing (you need a space after the comma) notwithstanding, a lot of people would find it decently funny, so I thought I would take this opportunity to write a bit about this pun, so to speak, from a linguistic angle, because, well, that&amp;rsquo;s what Linguistrix is all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kripayaa Samjho!</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/kripayaa-samjho/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/kripayaa-samjho/</guid>
      <description>Back in November, I discussed what happened when Tom Cruise used machine translation to connect to his Indians fans. Since I am in Japan, I come across bad English translations on a daily basis. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t posted any on Linguistrix because Chinglish/Janglish is very common stuff and you get them dime by the dozen. But today I found this one that is incomprehensible in at least two languages (I have to check up my Chinese friend to find out whether it makes any more sense in Chinese than it does in English/Hindi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dhoni aur chhakke</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/dhoni-aur-chhakke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 17:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/dhoni-aur-chhakke/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been online on FB/Twitter today, you must have noticed that the Indian part of the inter-web has gone crazy over a supposed screenshot from a Star News telecast. I say supposed because my Facebook feed has been flooded with all kinds of stupidity in the last few days—from images of Gods magically appearing on the top of mountains to claims that Louis Braille was an Italian king—so naturally I have developed a deep distrust of all society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Throwing the pasta out with the pasta water</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/throwing-the-pasta-out-with-the-pasta-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 09:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/throwing-the-pasta-out-with-the-pasta-water/</guid>
      <description>Back when we were in Canada, Ramu and I used to love ginger biscuits, whereas Sangram and Goel hated them, giving us the opportunity to finally use &#39;Bandar kya jaane adrak ka swaad&#39; (Wiki: Someone without refined tastes cannot appreciate a fine thing) literally. In general, however, I would rather not want to experience famous idioms and proverbs literally (sar mundaate hi ole pade [Facing the repercussions of an action right after you take it] would be particularly painful, especially since I once got caught in a terrible hailstorm in Stuttgart).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where’s the coffee in my strawberry latte?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/wheres-the-coffee-in-my-strawberry-latte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 03:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/02/wheres-the-coffee-in-my-strawberry-latte/</guid>
      <description>After 3 years of traveling alone and spending 2 years telling others how to do it, I did something as stupid as forgetting my bag in the bottom luggage hold of the bus after I got down at Kyoto station on the freezing cold morning of 27th January, 2012.
Luckily, I realized this within less than 2 minutes of getting down, and thus began a series of frenzied calls to a &amp;lsquo;Japanese Only&amp;rsquo; emergency number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stupid analogies are like stupid analogies</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/01/stupid-analogies-are-like-stupid-analogies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 17:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/01/stupid-analogies-are-like-stupid-analogies/</guid>
      <description>I have always had a love-hate relation with analogies, though it has mostly veered towards hate. I agree that they can occasionally be illuminating and can make difficult concepts more palatable, but I have often considered them evil and felt that they do more harm than good. Usually, they over-simplify a concept to &amp;ldquo;dumb it down&amp;rdquo;, so to speak, but end up creating easy-to-kill straw-men, or make arguments go into a tangent just because people start arguing over the analogy instead of the original premise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evacuating in an orderly fashion</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/01/evacuating-in-an-orderly-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 17:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/01/evacuating-in-an-orderly-fashion/</guid>
      <description>Last night, at about 2 a.m., I was jolted out of my sleep by a harsh sound. There seemed to be a lot of noise all around but I was too groggy to make sense of what was going on. When I came back to my senses a few seconds later, I began making sense of the noise—&amp;rsquo;FIRE! FIRE! THERE IS A FIRE ON THE FOURTH FLOOR! PLEASE EVACUATE IN AN ORDERLY FASHION&amp;rsquo;, followed by something similar in Japanese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarian’s Kolaveri</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/vegetarians-kolaveri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 11:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/vegetarians-kolaveri/</guid>
      <description>Enough. You have troubled us enough. Yes, you. Don’t run away. I am talking about you only.
Everytime you are going for dinner with us, you will be nuisance whole time. First you will make sarcastic comments—&amp;rdquo;Why are you looking in menu card? anyhow you will eat only paneer&amp;rdquo;. Then you will pounce on our food also. When waiter comes with non-veg food, you will give silly smiles and ask him to serve to you only but when he comes with veg food you will tell him to serve to everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My name is Khan. Kh. Kh. Kh. NOT from the epiglottis.</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/my-name-is-khan.-kh.-kh.-kh.-not-from-the-epiglottis./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 05:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/my-name-is-khan.-kh.-kh.-kh.-not-from-the-epiglottis./</guid>
      <description>This post should have come 1½ years ago, but Linguistrix wasn’t extant back then, and I only remembered this yesterday as a friend professed his love for Shahrukh Khan. And this needs to be on Linguistrix.
You all know the routine. The one time linguistics is mentioned in mainstream cinema, and it’s just plain wrong. If you’ve seen the movie, you’d know that the character Shahrukh plays makes a big deal about the fact that his name isn’t pronounced correctly, specifically the first sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Maids with Seven Mops—India and Internet Censorship</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/seven-maids-with-seven-mopsindia-and-internet-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 07:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/seven-maids-with-seven-mopsindia-and-internet-censorship/</guid>
      <description>Kapil Sibbal wants Facebook etc. to continuously monitor content so that anything that insults any one in the ruling party is nipped in the bud. And now, an Indian court has ordered FB and other social networking websites to remove offensive content by Feb 6. The plaintiff has submitted a CD full of objectionable content found on online media, and wants it removed.
Language and censorship go hand in hand. When you have people who want to say stuff, you have people who don&amp;rsquo;t want it being said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suarez, Evra and Racial Insults</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/suarez-evra-and-racial-insults/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 06:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/suarez-evra-and-racial-insults/</guid>
      <description>In what&amp;rsquo;s minty fresh news, Liverpool striker Suarez was given an 8-match ban for racially abusing Manchester United defender Patrice Evra. You may read about it here. Santosh Ananthakrishnan sent me the link to a discussion about the same on WebDiplomacy Forums.
I am a football n00b, and reading news reports about this incident has been an ordeal due to a bevy of unfamiliar names and abbreviations, but from what I have understood so far, the defence is that whatever Suarez called Evra is actually a playful and casual term where Suarez comes from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do languages change?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/how-do-languages-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/how-do-languages-change/</guid>
      <description>Ojas Patil suggested long ago that I write a post about causes of language change. I had forgotten it until E, who&amp;rsquo;s already given me post fodder once via a comment on a Linguistrix post, asked me a follow-up question on my reply to his comment-question. It was heartening to see that E appeared reasonably convinced by my answers to his first question, and his question is quite interesting—
 So how does language or grammar evolve (Because it certainly _does_ evolve)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pronunciation going awry</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/pronunciation-going-awry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 13:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/pronunciation-going-awry/</guid>
      <description>Christmas is around the corner, and it seems to be that time of the year when you discover you had been pronouncing a word wrongly all this time.
The word is awry, which I had always thought of as awe-ry, instead of its actual pronunciation a-wry (əˈraɪ).
The funny part is that I learnt of the correct pronunciation while reading someone else&amp;rsquo;s account of how he had been making the same mistake (for a much longer period than mine).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes something grammatical?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/what-makes-something-grammatical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 14:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/what-makes-something-grammatical/</guid>
      <description>Someone called E has posted a question in the comments section of my last post—The VanDamme Academy, and why grammar is not about clarity—Part 2. I was going to answer it there itself, but I realized this had enough material to be a post, so here it goes.
First, his question:
 So, what, according to you, is &amp;lsquo;unconditionally ungrammatical&amp;rsquo; about _They is walking_? If it conveys all the information the speaker intends to convey, unambiguously, the only thing wrong with it is the fact that it does not follow convention (the convention of conjugating a verb a certain way with certain subjects)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The VanDamme Academy, and why grammar is not about clarity—Part 2</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/the-vandamme-academy-and-why-grammar-is-not-about-claritypart-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 17:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/the-vandamme-academy-and-why-grammar-is-not-about-claritypart-2/</guid>
      <description>[This is Part 2 of the post title. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the first part, please read it here, though this post can be read in isolation too]
An important distinction that people often miss out on is the difference between _grammar_ and _style_—the difference between writing _correctly_ and writing well. And this distinction is very important because it&amp;rsquo;s more or less easy for most native speakers with some amount of training in the standard dialect (and knowledge of things like right spellings) to write correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The VanDamme Academy, and why grammar is not about clarity—Part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/the-vandamme-academy-and-why-grammar-is-not-about-claritypart-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/the-vandamme-academy-and-why-grammar-is-not-about-claritypart-1/</guid>
      <description>Miheer Desai suggested that I check out the Lisa VanDamme channel on YouTube for her views on parenting and teaching. I found the VanDamme Academy fairly interesting, and Ms VanDamme seems to be a very passionate person. Her video response to the Chinese Moms article was also thought-provoking, and it&amp;rsquo;s heartening to see that someone is putting an effort into improving pedagogy and understanding the ways in which we can educate kids in today&amp;rsquo;s world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greeting cards and virtual offices</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/greeting-cards-and-virtual-offices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 08:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/greeting-cards-and-virtual-offices/</guid>
      <description>Two small snippets today.
Our neighbours have a son who must be around 7–8 years old, the age when kids begin to facepalm over the many idiosyncrancies of the English spelling system. I found this stuck on their front door. What was funny was that this actually looks more like an IPA transcription. Of course, the [n] would actually be the velar nasal [ŋ], the [g] is usually there in Indian pronunciation but not in many other dialects and the second vowel would be [ɪ].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We aren’t the only ones with ‘infinite pains’</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/we-arent-the-only-ones-with-infinite-pains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 05:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/we-arent-the-only-ones-with-infinite-pains/</guid>
      <description>My views on IITB lingo have changed considerably over the years. I used to find it &amp;lsquo;positively revolting&amp;rsquo; in freshman year, and this slowly changed to &amp;lsquo;occasionally annoying&amp;rsquo; somewhere around third year, finally settling at &amp;lsquo;mostly harmless&amp;rsquo;. I am sure reams of paper have been devoted towards discussing campus lingo in general (there&amp;rsquo;s an entire Masters Thesis about IITM lingo, for instance), so I won&amp;rsquo;t discuss it here.
There are two reasons why I wrote this post, and critiquing IIT lingo isn&amp;rsquo;t either of them—firstly, I wanted to demonstrate how we can investigate simple issues surrounding language usage by using freely and publicly available tools and resources, and secondly, I wanted to talk about how this teaches us to never _assume_ things right-away when dealing with linguistic issues, but to adopt a scientific approach where we try to look at data to prove or disprove our claims instead of blindly trusting our intuition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to learn any language—Part 2 (Learning resources)</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/how-to-learn-any-languagepart-2-learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 08:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/how-to-learn-any-languagepart-2-learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>This article is the second article in the multi-part series The Tower of Babel Guide: How to learn any language
The first part dealt with the _whys_ and _whats_ that you might encounter when you decide to learn a language. In this part, we will talk about the kinds of resources you can use for learning languages, and their pros and cons.
Quite a few of you might have been taught a foreign language at school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Underwear to bahut pahni hain, lekin chaddi kabhi nahin</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/underwear-to-bahut-pahni-hain-lekin-chaddi-kabhi-nahin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 18:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/12/underwear-to-bahut-pahni-hain-lekin-chaddi-kabhi-nahin/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s some happy news on the personal front—I got placed recently, so I am likely to have more money in the future to spend on this blog! And ever since the 1st of December, I have been, as Oscar Wilde said, living entirely for pleasure. From having Starters only! lunches to spending the whole night playing weirdass games with friends, it&amp;rsquo;s been a great time so far.

In this post-placement decadence, I went to watch The Dirty Picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-car toons</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/anti-car-toons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 03:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/anti-car-toons/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Hindustan Times has an interesting pun (I am assuming it was intentional, though I won&amp;rsquo;t put my cash on it). For some reason, I find it weird, but at the same time it&amp;rsquo;s tough to say why.

One reason is that I usually associate the word _toon_ with cartoon movies, not comic strips or paper characters. I checked this with a couple of online dictionaries, and they supported my intuition—</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tower of Babel Guide (or How to learn any language): Part 1</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/the-tower-of-babel-guide-or-how-to-learn-any-language-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 15:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/the-tower-of-babel-guide-or-how-to-learn-any-language-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I have planned a multi-part series on the topic of learning languages. It is aimed at serving two purposes—answering questions around this issue that many people have asked me in the past few years, and putting into words my observations of what worked best for me or others around me, and where I felt I or others could have done better. The series will roughly address the following issues—</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Why this Kolaveri Di]-u?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/why-this-kolaveri-di-u/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 14:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/why-this-kolaveri-di-u/</guid>
      <description>Since everyone and their grandmother is busy listening to Why this Kolaveri Di for the 4157th time in 3 days (What! You haven&amp;rsquo;t heard it yet? Get out from under that rock already!), I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write this short note on a couple of points of linguistic interest in that song.

Apart from the extremely catchy tune that refuses to get out of your head even when you are asleep (I am sure loads of people have this song running like a sinister background score in their dreams), one of the things that make this song fun is of course the strongly Tamil accented English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The WTF files—Jimmy Wales on Latin</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/the-wtf-filesjimmy-wales-on-latin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 05:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/the-wtf-filesjimmy-wales-on-latin/</guid>
      <description>The first entry on the WTF files on Linguistrix is supposedly a quote by Jimmy Wales published in today&amp;rsquo;s HT (Wikipedia woos India with local languages). I say supposedly because I really hope that this attribution is incorrect, that this is the result of stupid paraphrasing, and that Jimmy Wales didn&amp;rsquo;t actually say something so hopelessly asinine—
 “In languages such as Latin, expressing an idea becomes difficult because the language is not commonly spoken and written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sheldon and Quadruple Negation</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/sheldon-and-quadruple-negation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 11:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/sheldon-and-quadruple-negation/</guid>
      <description>Yay! A few weeks ago, I wrote about how a newspaper article in the HT messed up a sentence due to too many negative particles and ended up meaning exactly the opposite of what was intended. On the other side of the spectrum is a dialogue from The Big Bang Theory&amp;rsquo;s latest episode (S05E10, The Flaming Spittoon Acquisition). The moment I heard it, I whooped with excitement—a perfectly executed quadruple negative, I thought, just as Amy pointed it out for the whole world to notice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anil Kapoor चट्टानों MI4!</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/anil-kapoor-%E0%A4%9A%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%9F%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%A8%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%82-mi4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 06:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/anil-kapoor-%E0%A4%9A%E0%A4%9F%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%9F%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%A8%E0%A5%8B%E0%A4%82-mi4/</guid>
      <description>A recent tweet by Tom Cruise shows us the perils of machine translation and literal translation.
The first part of the tweet is of course absolutely unidiomatic, but you can figure out what it is trying to say. But the second part will flummox any reader who is not familiar with English expressions. This was obviously the result of English—&amp;gt;Hindi machine translation of something like &amp;ldquo;We are really looking forward to talking to our friends in India when @GhostProtocol comes out soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pronouncing proper nouns, like a boss!</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/pronouncing-proper-nouns-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 05:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/pronouncing-proper-nouns-like-a-boss/</guid>
      <description>Sanyam wrote in to ask: &amp;rsquo;Is it true, that we can pronounce proper nouns as we deem fit?&amp;rsquo;
As far as I understand from my experience at school, this &amp;lsquo;myth&amp;rsquo; is more a result of school kids trying to excuse themselves of pronouncing English names correctly by resorting to a bogey rule that you can pronounce a proper noun the way you want. Here&amp;rsquo;s my personal take on this—
In short, I would say, &amp;lsquo;an individual has the right to assert that a particular sequence of sounds (and its corresponding transcription) is their name&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let us speak our Inglish</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/let-us-speak-our-inglish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 08:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/11/let-us-speak-our-inglish/</guid>
      <description>You see, when I started this blog, I swore to myself that I will try to maintain as civil a tone as possible, and shall only strive to increase awareness about a field that I hold so dear. Hold the _lamp of knowledge_ (and a couple of more fancy metaphors that our school prayers taught us), that is.
And this is why I revised the beginning of this post:
What addles the heads of smart Why do people spout absolute Karan Thapar is a man of great erudition and a delight to watch when he is taking politicians apart with his sharp wit and steely demeanor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Momentarily outraged but humbled momentarily</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/momentarily-outraged-but-humbled-momentarily/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 02:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/momentarily-outraged-but-humbled-momentarily/</guid>
      <description>Pritish told me yesterday that, when he posted on a Google Group, he got this message
 &amp;ldquo;Your message will appear in SymphonyxIITB momentarily.&amp;rdquo;
 My (and Pritish&amp;rsquo;s, I presume, from his responses) first instinct was this was obviously wrong. In my idiolect, _momentarily_ could only be used for the sense _&amp;lsquo;for a moment&amp;rsquo;_ whereas Google was using it for &amp;lsquo;in a moment&amp;rsquo;. Google is not averse to relatively weird constructions as was discussed in this post on LanguageLog, so I presumed this was the case here too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All 6 days except Saturday</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/all-6-days-except-saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 18:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/all-6-days-except-saturday/</guid>
      <description>I saw this at Port Blair airport today, on my way back from an excellent family vacation at Andaman and Nicobar Islands. Language errors on notices and boards are very common and are tracked by countless blogs and humor websites. Since most of these follow typical patterns like spelling mistakes (MISSILE PAAV or anything any IITB Hostel Canteen menu lists) or bad grammar, they are funny but mostly unremarkable. However, I am posting this one here since I have the feeling that this wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much a result of lack of competence as plain confusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who knows about whom?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/who-knows-about-whom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 17:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/who-knows-about-whom/</guid>
      <description>Sindhu, a lawyer friend, sent me this on chat:
 You should do a post on who v. whom. VERY confusing, I say!
 &amp;#8230; to which I replied that she didn&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about it and as long as she trusted her instinct, it was just fine, but she said:
 Yes, but it is important to know the difference. At our firm, we are very particular about pristine English in mails to clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No reason to disbelieve that this is a misnegation</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/no-reason-to-disbelieve-that-this-is-a-misnegation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 07:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/no-reason-to-disbelieve-that-this-is-a-misnegation/</guid>
      <description>New day, new linguistic fodder to chew on, and another quick note!
From an article in today&amp;rsquo;s HT:
 &amp;ldquo;The SC had said that if there is no reason to disbelieve that the accused cannot be reformed or rehabilitated, a sentence of death would be erroneous.&amp;rdquo;
 The moment I read &amp;lsquo;no reason to disbelieve&amp;rsquo;, I knew there was a disaster waiting to happen, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed. There are a total of 4 negating elements in this text (no reason, disbelieve, cannot be, erroneous) and you will see that the meaning is virtually impossible to compute naturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black flag-waving</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/black-flag-waving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 03:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/black-flag-waving/</guid>
      <description>Another quick note while I spend my days doing uninteresting things.
The front page of Hindustan Times today described another in the series of slipper-hurling incidents that have become quite fashionable in the last few years. This time, the hurl-ee, so to speak, was Arvind Kejriwal. The report reads—
 &amp;ldquo;The black flag-waving, saffron kurta-clad attacker, XYZ of Jalaun district, Bundelkhand, about 200 km north of Lucknow, attacked Kejriwal when he was about to reach the dais at Jhulelal park near Lucknow University to address a meeting on graft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Ideas</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/green-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 18:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/green-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Colourless Green Ideas Sleep Furiously is perhaps the most famous sentence in all of Linguistics, given by Noam Chomsky to demonstrate the difference between syntax and semantics—a perfectly grammatical sentence with no understandable meaning, as Wikipedia describes it. I was reminded of it today when I was listening to the song _Aazaadiyaan_ from the movie Udaan.
Back in 1985, a competition was held at Stanford where participants were asked to provide a paragraph or verse that could give enough context to make this sentence meaningful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Swedish Embassy</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/indian-swedish-embassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 05:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/indian-swedish-embassy/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick note rather than an elaborate post—I was eating at Shakti (the Women&amp;rsquo;s Cell run lunch center at IITB) yesterday when a group sitting next to me was discussing what they perceived as a semantic ambiguity. The issue was the right term for the Swedish Embassy situated in India. Would it be the Indian Swedish Embassy, or the Swedish Indian Embassy? From what I observed, opinion was divided, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether both sides really computed different meanings or whether one was just trying to play the Devil&amp;rsquo;s Advocate, trying to defend what might originally have been a mistaken utterance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Cares</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/nobody-cares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2011 07:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/10/nobody-cares/</guid>
      <description>I am surprised I didn&amp;rsquo;t come across this much earlier. Jonathan Swift, a very renowned essayist, poet, satirist, popularly known as the author of Gulliver&amp;rsquo;s Travels, wrote:   If you want to read it yourself, you can do so here, but I would advise against it. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much to be gained, and he&amp;rsquo;s written too much. Jonathan Swift was an intelligent man, and a pretty good writer, so read up his other stuff if you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poshchim Bongo</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/poshchim-bongo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 18:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/poshchim-bongo/</guid>
      <description>Well, West Bengal recently renamed itself to Poshchim Bongo (পশ্চিমবঙ্গ; pronounced [poʃtʃim bɔŋɡo]). Inhabitants of a place should have the first say about what their place is called, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see any problem there. And a community can choose whatever pronunciation they want, as I had discussed in a previous post. Of course, one would expect that it is worth the millions in taxpayer money that would be spent in the re-branding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose Hindi is it?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/whose-hindi-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 13:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/whose-hindi-is-it/</guid>
      <description>[This article has undergone a few edits after being published. I see that the whole discussion is revolving around issues peripheral to the theme of the post. In this post, I am denouncing the concept of purity being attached to Sanskritized Hindi, so I have removed bits I care less about and which are not directly relevant to the issue.]
14th September is celebrated in India as Hindi Divas (हिंदी दिवस).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanskr[i|u]t</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/sanskriut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 17:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/sanskriut/</guid>
      <description>You may have observed that most speakers of Hindi pronounce ऋ as essentially रि [rɪ] thus pronouncing words like ऋषभ or कृषि or आकृति as रिषभ, क्रिषि and आक्रिति respectively while speakers of Marathi and Gujarati pronounce it as रु [rʊ] thus saying रुषभ, क्रुषि and आक्रुती. It is a completely different matter that most Hindi speakers do not pronounce ष as a distinct sound. They use the same sound for ष and श, roughly the voiceless post-alveolar fricative, which also explains why most of us spent a lot of sweat and blood in memorizing when a word had श and when it had ष—there were no phonetic clues to differentiate between what was essentially a spelling distinction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fascinating world of languages, 2</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 07:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-2/</guid>
      <description>[This is the continuation of a series of articles on Languages and Linguistics that I am writing for a magazine for school kids, EducationEdge, that a friend of mine has started recently. These articles are targeted at students of classes VIII to XII. I will keep posting those articles on Linguistrix once they are published. The first article can be found here.]
In the previous article, I introduced you to Linguistics and discussed a few examples from various fields within this discipline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fascinating world of languages, 1</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 06:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-1/</guid>
      <description>[I am writing a series of articles on Languages and Linguistics for a magazine for school kids, EducationEdge, that a friend of mine has started recently. These articles are targeted at students of classes VIII to XII. I will keep posting those articles on Linguistrix once they are published. Here&#39;s the first in the series.]  “Those who know nothing of foreign languages know nothing of their own.”
—Johann Wolfgang von Goethe  Every human possesses an innate ability to acquire language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howdy</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/08/howdy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 16:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/08/howdy/</guid>
      <description>This blog has been in the proverbial pipeline for the past 3–4 months now, and after spending a lot of time on possible names, I finalized what was actually the first name that came to my mind—Linguistrix. I won&amp;rsquo;t explain the funda—if you don&amp;rsquo;t get it, it isn&amp;rsquo;t anything great anyway.
Anyhow, the blog&amp;rsquo;s all set up, and I will hopefully start posting soon.
This blog apparently supports LaTeX off the fly!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>