<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non Linguistics on Linguistrix</title>
    <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/categories/non-linguistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non Linguistics on Linguistrix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 07:49:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.linguistrix.com/categories/non-linguistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The critical mass of goodness</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/the-critical-mass-of-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 07:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/the-critical-mass-of-goodness/</guid>
      <description>The country was galvanized last year by the whole Jan Lokpal Movement, and a lot was said for and against the movement, its leaders and cheerleaders, and the thousands of Indians who poured into the streets in the largest display of public outrage in recent times. While we are all fashionably outraged at the way politicians misuse public money with impunity, a small look at the way we lead our daily lives is enough to show that what happens in the order of millions of rupees is just a bigger manifestation of a phenomenon that is integral to our everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you think it’s disgusting, too bad for you.</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/if-you-think-its-disgusting-too-bad-for-you./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 19:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/03/if-you-think-its-disgusting-too-bad-for-you./</guid>
      <description>[This post is second in the series of general posts on Linguistrix (the first one was Stupid Analogues are like Stupid Analogies). I choose to include such posts on the blog because I find the topic to be of significant intellectual/academic interest.]        [This post is second in the series of general posts on Linguistrix (the first one was Stupid Analogues are like Stupid Analogies).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stupid analogies are like stupid analogies</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/01/stupid-analogies-are-like-stupid-analogies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 17:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2012/01/stupid-analogies-are-like-stupid-analogies/</guid>
      <description>I have always had a love-hate relation with analogies, though it has mostly veered towards hate. I agree that they can occasionally be illuminating and can make difficult concepts more palatable, but I have often considered them evil and felt that they do more harm than good. Usually, they over-simplify a concept to &amp;ldquo;dumb it down&amp;rdquo;, so to speak, but end up creating easy-to-kill straw-men, or make arguments go into a tangent just because people start arguing over the analogy instead of the original premise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>