<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Educationedge Articles on Linguistrix</title>
    <link>https://linguistrix.github.io/categories/educationedge-articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Educationedge Articles on Linguistrix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 07:03:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://linguistrix.github.io/categories/educationedge-articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The fascinating world of languages, 2</title>
      <link>https://linguistrix.github.io/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 07:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://linguistrix.github.io/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-2/</guid>
      <description>[This is the continuation of a series of articles on Languages and Linguistics that I am writing for a magazine for school kids, EducationEdge, that a friend of mine has started recently. These articles are targeted at students of classes VIII to XII. I will keep posting those articles on Linguistrix once they are published. The first article can be found here.]
In the previous article, I introduced you to Linguistics and discussed a few examples from various fields within this discipline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fascinating world of languages, 1</title>
      <link>https://linguistrix.github.io/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 06:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://linguistrix.github.io/2011/09/the-fascinating-world-of-languages-1/</guid>
      <description>[I am writing a series of articles on Languages and Linguistics for a magazine for school kids, EducationEdge, that a friend of mine has started recently. These articles are targeted at students of classes VIII to XII. I will keep posting those articles on Linguistrix once they are published. Here&#39;s the first in the series.]  “Those who know nothing of foreign languages know nothing of their own.”
—Johann Wolfgang von Goethe  Every human possesses an innate ability to acquire language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>