<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scripts on Linguistrix</title>
    <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/categories/scripts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scripts on Linguistrix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 15:35:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.linguistrix.com/categories/scripts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another woe of non-phonetic writing systems</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2017/01/yet-another-woe-of-non-phonetic-writing-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 15:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2017/01/yet-another-woe-of-non-phonetic-writing-systems/</guid>
      <description>I was in Mexico last week and was quite excited to try my Spanish there. I studied some Spanish 3–4 years ago using Michel Thomas courses, and did a few levels on Duolingo, and combined with my French, I can get a general sense of simple written Spanish, but I had literally zero on-ground speaking experience. There are plenty of Spanish speakers in California, so it&amp;rsquo;s not difficult at all to find people to chat with if you really care, but it somehow never happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should be India’s common script?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/07/what-should-be-indias-common-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 17:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2016/07/what-should-be-indias-common-script/</guid>
      <description>I have a lot of interest in writing systems, which is why you will find a lot of posts on this blog around them. A few years ago, I wrote about the Bharati script, which was touted as an attempt to create a universal script for Indian languages. I had expressed measured skepticism about the idea, but had also said I would like to see the script, and luckily, was contacted by Chetan Shenoy, an undergrad from IIT Madras, who works under Prof Chakravarthy, the creator of the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One script to bind them all</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/07/one-script-to-bind-them-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/07/one-script-to-bind-them-all/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, I came across a few news reports that a professor from IIT Madras (Professor V Srinivas Chakravarthy) has developed a script (called Bharati) to &amp;ldquo;unify 22 Indian languages&amp;rdquo;. As a script-enthusiast, I was of course slightly interested.
There is a lot of self-congratulatory rhetoric in India about how Indian scripts are very &amp;lsquo;scientific&amp;rsquo;. On the contrary, the English script (which, in most cases, is the only other kind of script most Indians know) is criticized for being arbitrary, ambiguous, unscientific, what have you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could better science reporting standards at the BBC improve the quality of their articles?</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/02/could-better-science-reporting-standards-at-the-bbc-improve-the-quality-of-their-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 19:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2013/02/could-better-science-reporting-standards-at-the-bbc-improve-the-quality-of-their-articles/</guid>
      <description>I just came across this article on the BBC Website (Could a new phonetic alphabet promote world peace?) because it was posted in the /r/badlinguistics sub-reddit, and for good reason.
It is such a remarkable mix of bad linguistics and general cluelessness that I would have thought that even with media&amp;rsquo;s generally low standards of science (especially language) reporting, something like this would not have made the cut.
First of all, I am not sure why they even chose to write a whole article around this SaypU thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poshchim Bongo</title>
      <link>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/poshchim-bongo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 18:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.linguistrix.com/2011/09/poshchim-bongo/</guid>
      <description>Well, West Bengal recently renamed itself to Poshchim Bongo (পশ্চিমবঙ্গ; pronounced [poʃtʃim bɔŋɡo]). Inhabitants of a place should have the first say about what their place is called, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see any problem there. And a community can choose whatever pronunciation they want, as I had discussed in a previous post. Of course, one would expect that it is worth the millions in taxpayer money that would be spent in the re-branding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>